<CORRECT>
    <EDITOR>Valerie Johnson</EDITOR>
    <PREAMB>
      <PRTPAGE P="5075"/>
      <AGENCY TYPE="F">DEPARTMENT OF COMMERCE</AGENCY>
      <SUBAGY>International Trade Administration</SUBAGY>
      <DEPDOC>[A-823-808]</DEPDOC>
      <SUBJECT>Ammendment to the Agreement Between the United States Department of Commerce and the Government of Ukraine Suspending the Antidumping Investigation on Cut-to-Length Carbon Steel Plate from Ukraine</SUBJECT>
    </PREAMB>
    <SUPLINF>
      <HD SOURCE="HD2">Correction</HD>
      <P>In notice document 03-526 beginning on page 1438 in the issue of Friday, January 10, 2003, make the following corrections:</P>
      <P>1. On page 1439, in the first column, in the sixth line from the bottom, &#x201C;December 20, 2002&#x201D; should read, &#x201C;January 2, 2003&#x201D;.</P>
      <P>2. On the same page, in the same column, after the signature section, please insert the following text:~</P>
      <HD SOURCE="HD1">Amendment to the Antidumping Suspension Agreement on Certain Cut-to-Length Carbon Steel Plate Between the United States Department of Commerce and the Government of Ukraine</HD>
      <P>The United States Department of Commerce (the Department) and the Government of Ukraine hereby amend section XII of the Agreement Suspending the Antidumping Investigation on Certain Cut-to-Length Carbon Steel Plate from Ukraine, signed October 24, 1997, by adding the following language immediately after the first sentence of section XII:</P>
      <P>In order to provide for the continuation of exports of cut-to-length plate from Ukraine to the United States during and immediately following the five-year review by the Department and the International Trade Commission pursuant to section 751(c) of the Tariff Act, the export limits provided for in section III of this Agreement shall remain in force through November 1, 2003.</P>
      <P>If, after said date, the underlying proceeding remains suspended, the Government of Ukraine and the Department will enter into consultations to agree upon export limits in order to permit future shipments under the Agreement.  If, prior to said date, the underlying proceeding is terminated as a result of the sunset review or the administrative review, the Agreement, this Amendment and the export limits contained therein will be terminated.</P>
      <SIG>
        <P>For the United States Department of Commerce.</P>
        <DATED>Dated: December 20, 2002.</DATED>
        <NAME>Faryar Shirzad,</NAME>
        <TITLE>Assistant Secretary for Import Administration.</TITLE>
        <P>For the Ministry of Economy and European Integration of Ukraine.</P>
        <DATED>Dated: December 20, 2002.</DATED>
        <NAME>Andriy I. Goncharuk,</NAME>
        <TITLE>State Secretary on Trade,Ministry of Economy and European Integration of Ukraine.</TITLE>
      </SIG>
      
    </SUPLINF>
    <FRDOC>[FR Doc. C3-526 Filed 1-30-03; 8:45 am]</FRDOC>
    <BILCOD>BILLING CODE 1505-01-D</BILCOD>
    <EDITOR>!!!Zara!!!</EDITOR>
    <PREAMB>
      <AGENCY TYPE="S">FEDERAL ELECTION COMMISSION</AGENCY>
      <CFR>11 CFR Part 104</CFR>
      <DEPDOC>[Notice 2002-26]</DEPDOC>
      <SUBJECT>Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 2002 Reporting</SUBJECT>
    </PREAMB>
    <SUPLINF>
      <HD SOURCE="HD2">Correction</HD>
      <P>In rule document 03-91 beginning on page 421 in the issue of Friday, January 3, 2003, make the following correction:</P>
      <SECTION>
        <SECTNO>&#xA7;104.20</SECTNO>
        <SUBJECT>[Corrected]</SUBJECT>
        <P>On page 419, in the third column, in &#xA7;104.20 (a)(5), &#x201C;11 CFR 100.29(a)(3)&#x201D;, should read &#x201C;11 CFR 100.29 (b)(3)&#x201D;.</P>
        
      </SECTION>
    </SUPLINF>
    <FRDOC>[FR Doc. C3-91 Filed 1-30-03; 8:45 am]</FRDOC>
    <BILCOD>BILLING CODE 1505-01-D</BILCOD>
    <EDITOR>!!!Zara!!!</EDITOR>
    <PREAMB>
      <AGENCY TYPE="S">DEPARTMENT OF JUSTICE</AGENCY>
      <DEPDOC>[AAG/A Order No. 003-2003]</DEPDOC>
      <SUBJECT>Privacy Act of 1974; System of Records</SUBJECT>
    </PREAMB>
    <SUPLINF>
      <HD SOURCE="HD2">Correction</HD>
      <P>In notice document 03-1671 beginning on page 3894 in the issue of Monday, January 27, 2003, make the following correction:</P>

      <P>On page 3894, in the third column, in the first three lines &#x201C;[insert date 30 days after publication in the<E T="04">Federal Register</E>]&#x201D;, should read &#x201C;February 26, 2003&#x201D;.</P>
      
    </SUPLINF>
    <FRDOC>[FR Doc. C3-1671 Filed 1-30-03; 8:45 am]</FRDOC>
    <BILCOD>BILLING CODE 1505-01-D</BILCOD>
    <EDITOR>!!!Zara!!!</EDITOR>
    <PREAMB>
      <AGENCY TYPE="S">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</AGENCY>
      <SUBAGY>Office of the Comptroller o fthe Currency</SUBAGY>
      <CFR>12 CFR Part 19</CFR>
      <DEPDOC>[Docket No. 02-15]</DEPDOC>
      <RIN>RIN 1557-AB43</RIN>
      <AGENCY TYPE="F">BOARD OF GOVERNORS OF THE FEDERAL RESERVE SYSTEM</AGENCY>
      <CFR>12 CFR Part 263</CFR>
      <DEPDOC>[Docket No. R-1139]</DEPDOC>
      <AGENCY TYPE="F">FEDERAL DEPOSIT INSURANCE CORPORATION</AGENCY>
      <CFR>12 CFR Part 308</CFR>
      <RIN>RIN 3064-AC57</RIN>
      <AGENCY TYPE="F">DEPARTMENT OF THE TREASURY</AGENCY>
      <SUBAGY>Office of Thrift Supervision</SUBAGY>
      <CFR>12 CFR Part 513</CFR>
      <DEPDOC>[No. 2002-58]</DEPDOC>
      <RIN>RIN 1550-AB53</RIN>
      <SUBJECT>Removal, Suspension, and Debarment of Accountants From Performing Audit Services</SUBJECT>
    </PREAMB>
    <SUPLINF>
      <HD SOURCE="HD2">Correction</HD>
      <P>In proposed rule document 03-98 beginning on page 1116 in the issue of Wednesday, January 8, 2003, make the following correction:</P>
      <P>On page 1117, in the third column, above the footnotes, in the last line, after &#x201C;effective;<SU>11</SU>&#x201D;, add &#x201C;engages&#x201D;.</P>
      
    </SUPLINF>
    <FRDOC>[FR Doc. C3-98 Filed 1-30-03; 8:45 am]</FRDOC>
    <BILCOD>BILLING CODE 1505-01-D</BILCOD>
  </CORRECT>