<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="cfr.xsl"?>
<CFRGRANULE xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="CFRMergedXML.xsd">
  <FDSYS>
    <CFRTITLE>11</CFRTITLE>
    <CFRTITLETEXT>Federal Elections</CFRTITLETEXT>
    <VOL>1</VOL>
    <DATE>1997-01-01</DATE>
    <ORIGINALDATE>1997-01-01</ORIGINALDATE>
    <COVERONLY>false</COVERONLY>
    <TITLE>COMPLIANCE PROCEDURE (2 U.S.C. 437g, 437d(a))</TITLE>
    <GRANULENUM>111</GRANULENUM>
    <HEADING>PART 111</HEADING>
    <ANCESTORS>
      <PARENT HEADING="" SEQ="2"/>
      <PARENT HEADING="" SEQ="1"/>
      <PARENT HEADING="SUBCHAPTER A" SEQ="0">GENERAL</PARENT>
    </ANCESTORS>
  </FDSYS>
  <PART>
    <HD SOURCE="HED">PART 111—COMPLIANCE PROCEDURE (2 U.S.C. 437g, 437d(a))</HD>
    <CONTENTS>
      <SECHD>Sec.</SECHD>
      <SECTNO>111.1</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Scope (2 U.S.C. 437g).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.2</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Computation of time.</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.3</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Initiation of compliance matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1), (2)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.4</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Complaints (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.5</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Initial complaint processing; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.6</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Opportunity to demonstrate that no action should be taken on complaint-generated matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.7</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>General Counsel's recommendation on complaint-generated matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.8</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Internally generated matters; referrals (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.9</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The reason to believe finding; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.10</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Investigation (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.11</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Written questions under order (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.12</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum; depositions (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(3), (4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.13</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Service of subpoenas, orders and notifications (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(3), (4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.14</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Witness fees and mileage (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(5)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.15</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Motions to quash or modify a subpoena (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(3), (4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.16</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The probable cause to believe recommendation; briefing procedures (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(3)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.17</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The probable cause to believe finding; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.18</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Conciliation (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.19</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Civil proceedings (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(6)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.20</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Public disclosure of Commission action (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.21</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Confidentiality (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(12)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.22</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Ex parte communications.</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>111.23</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Representation by counsel; notification.</SUBJECT>
    </CONTENTS>
    <AUTH>
      <HD SOURCE="HED">Authority: </HD>
      <P>2 U.S.C. 437g, 437d(a), 438(a)(8).</P>
    </AUTH>
    <SOURCE>
      <HD SOURCE="HED">Source: </HD>
      <P>45 FR 15120, Mar. 7, 1980, unless otherwise noted.</P>
    </SOURCE>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.1</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Scope (2 U.S.C. 437g).</SUBJECT>

      <P>These regulations provide procedures for processing possible violations of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as amended (2 U.S.C. 431, <E T="03">et seq.</E>) and chapters 95 and 96 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 (26 U.S.C. 9001, <E T="03">et seq.</E> and 9031 <E T="03">et seq.</E>).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.2</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Computation of time.</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) <E T="03">General rule.</E> In computing any period of time prescribed or allowed by this part, the day of the act, event, or <PRTPAGE P="141"/>default from which the designated period of time begins to run shall not be included. The last day of the period so computed shall be included, unless it is a Saturday, a Sunday, or a legal holiday. As used in this section, the term <E T="03">legal holiday</E> includes New Year's Day, President's Day, Memorial Day, Independence Day, Labor Day, Columbus Day, Veterans Day, Thanksgiving Day, Christmas Day, and any other day appointed as a holiday for employees of the United States by the President or the Congress of the United States.</P>
      <P>(b) <E T="03">Special rule for periods less than seven days.</E> When the period of time prescribed or allowed is less than seven (7) days, intermediate Saturdays, Sundays, and legal holidays shall be excluded in the computation.</P>
      <P>(c) <E T="03">Special rule for service by mail.</E> Whenever the Commission or any person has the right or is required to do some act within a prescribed period after the service of any paper by or upon the Commission or such person and the paper is served by or upon the Commission or such person by mail, three (3) days shall be added to the prescribed period.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.3</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Initiation of compliance matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1), (2)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Compliance matters may be initiated by a complaint or on the basis of information ascertained by the Commission in the normal course of carrying out its supervisory responsibilities.</P>
      <P>(b) Matters initiated by complaint are subject to the provisions of 11 CFR 111.4 through 111.7. Matters initiated on the basis of information ascertained by the Commission in the normal course of carrying out its supervisory responsibilities are subject to the provisions of 11 CFR 111.8. All compliance matters are subject to the provisions of 11 CFR 111.2 and 111.9 through 111.23.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.4</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Complaints (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Any person who believes that a violation of any statute or regulation over which the Commission has jurisdiction has occurred or is about to occur may file a complaint in writing to the General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. If possible, three (3) copies should be submitted.</P>
      <P>(b) A complaint shall comply with the following:</P>
      <P>(1) It shall provide the full name and address of the complainant; and</P>
      <P>(2) The contents of the complaint shall be sworn to and signed in the presence of a notary public and shall be notarized.</P>
      <P>(c) All statements made in a complaint are subject to the statutes governing perjury and to 18 U.S.C. 1001. The complaint should differentiate between statements based upon personal knowledge and statements based upon information and belief.</P>
      <P>(d) The complaint should conform to the following provisions:</P>
      <P>(1) It should clearly identify as a respondent each person or entity who is alleged to have committed a violation;</P>
      <P>(2) Statements which are not based upon personal knowledge should be accompanied by an identification of the source of information which gives rise to the complainants belief in the truth of such statements;</P>
      <P>(3) It should contain a clear and concise recitation of the facts which describe a violation of a statute or regulation over which the Commission has jurisdiction; and</P>
      <P>(4) It should be accompanied by any documentation supporting the facts alleged if such documentation is known of, or available to, the complainant.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15120, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.5</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Initial complaint processing; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Upon receipt of a complaint, the General Counsel shall review the complaint for substantial compliance with the technical requirements of 11 CFR 111.4, and, if it complies with those requirements shall within five (5) days after receipt notify each respondent that the complaint has been filed, advise them of Commission compliance procedures, and enclose a copy of the complaint.</P>

      <P>(b) If a complaint does not comply with the requirements of 11 CFR 111.4, the General Counsel shall so notify the complainant and any person(s) or entity(ies) identified therein as respondent(s), within the five (5) day period <PRTPAGE P="142"/>specified in 11 CFR 111.5(a), that no action shall be taken on the basis of that complaint. A copy of the complaint shall be enclosed with the notification to each respondent.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.6</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Opportunity to demonstrate that no action should be taken on complaint-generated matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) A respondent shall be afforded an opportunity to demonstrate that no action should be taken on the basis of a complaint by submitting, within fifteen (15) days from receipt of a copy of the complaint, a letter or memorandum setting forth reasons why the Commission should take no action.</P>
      <P>(b) The Commission shall not take any action, or make any finding, against a respondent other than action dismissing the complaint, unless it has considered such response or unless no such response has been served upon the Commission within the fifteen (15) day period specified in 11 CFR 111.6(a).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.7</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>General Counsel's recommendation on complaint-generated matters (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Following either the expiration of the fifteen (15) day period specified by 11 CFR 111.6(a) or the receipt of a response as specified by 11 CFR 111.6(a), whichever occurs first, the General Counsel may recommend to the Commission whether or not it should find reason to believe that a respondent has committed or is about to commit a violation of statutes or regulations over which the Commission has jurisdiction.</P>
      <P>(b) The General Counsel may recommend that the Commission find that there is no reason to believe that a violation has been committed or is about to be committed, or that the Commission otherwise dismiss a complaint without regard to the provisions of 11 CFR 111.6(a).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.8</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Internally generated matters; referrals (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) On the basis of information ascertained by the Commission in the normal course of carrying out its supervisory responsibilities, or on the basis of a referral from an agency of the United States or of any state, the General Counsel may recommend in writing that the Commission find reason to believe that a person or entity has committed or is about to commit a violation of statutes or regulations over which the Commission has jurisdiction.</P>
      <P>(b) If the Commission finds reason to believe that a violation has occurred or is about to occur the notification to respondent required by 11 CFR 111.9(a) shall include a copy of a staff report setting forth the legal basis and the alleged facts which support the Commission's action.</P>
      <P>(c) Prior to taking any action pursuant to this section against any person who has failed to file a disclosure report required by 11 CFR 104.5(a)(1)(iii) for the calendar quarter immediately preceding the election involved or by § 104.5(a)(1)(i), the Commission shall notify such person of failure to file the required reports. If a satisfactory response is not received within four (4) business days, the Commission shall publish before the election the name of the person and the report or reports such person has failed to file.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15120, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 45 FR 21210, Apr. 1, 1980]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.9</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The reason to believe finding; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) If the Commission, either after reviewing a complaint-generated recommendation as described in 11 CFR 111.7 and any response of a respondent submitted pursuant to 11 CFR 111.6, or after reviewing an internally-generated recommendation as described in 11 CFR 111.8, determines by an affirmative vote of four (4) of its members that it has reason to believe that a respondent has violated a statute or regulation over which the Commission has jurisdiction, its Chairman or Vice Chairman shall notify such respondent of the Commission's finding by letter, setting forth the sections of the statute or regulations alleged to have been violated and the alleged factual basis supporting the finding.</P>

      <P>(b) If the Commission finds no reason to believe, or otherwise terminates its proceedings, the General Counsel shall so advise both complainant and respondent by letter.<PRTPAGE P="143"/>
      </P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.10</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Investigation (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) An investigation shall be conducted in any case in which the Commission finds reason to believe that a violation of a statute or regulation over which the Commission has jurisdiction has occurred or is about to occur.</P>
      <P>(b) In its investigation, the Commission may utilize the provisions of 11 CFR 111.11 through 111.15. The investigation may include, but is not limited to, field investigations, audits, and other methods of information-gathering.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.11</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Written questions under order (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>The Commission may authorize its Chairman or Vice Chairman to issue an order requiring any person to submit sworn written answers to written questions and may specify a date by which such answers must be submitted.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.12</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Subpoenas and subpoenas duces tecum; depositions (2 U.S.C. 437d(a) (3), (4)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) The Commission may authorize its Chairman or Vice Chairman to issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of any person by deposition and to issue subpoenas duces tecum for the production of documentary or other tangible evidence in connection with a deposition or otherwise.</P>
      <P>(b) If oral testimony is ordered to be taken by deposition or documents are ordered to be produced, the subpoena shall so state and shall advise the deponent or person subpoenaed that all testimony will be under oath. A deposition may be taken before any person having the power to administer oaths.</P>
      <P>(c) The Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, Rule 30(e), shall govern the opportunity to review and sign depositions taken pursuant to this section.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.13</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Service of subpoenas, orders and notifications (2 U.S.C. 437d(a) (3), (4)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Service of a subpoena, order or notification upon a person named therein shall be made by delivering a copy to that person in the manner described by 11 CFR 111.13 (b), (c), and (d). In the case of subpoenas, fees for one day's attendance and mileage shall be tendered as specified in 11 CFR 111.14.</P>
      <P>(b) Whenever service is to be made upon a person who has advised the Commission of representation by an attorney pursuant to 11 CFR 111.23, the service shall be made upon the attorney by any of the methods specified in 11 CFR 111.13(c).</P>
      <P>(c) Delivery of subpoenas, orders and notifications to a natural person may be made by handing a copy to the person, or leaving a copy at his or her office with the person in charge thereof, by leaving a copy at his or her dwelling place or usual place of abode with some person of suitable age and discretion residing therein, or by mailing a copy by registered or certified mail to his or her last known address, or by any other method whereby actual notice is given.</P>
      <P>(d) When the person to be served is not a natural person delivery of subpoenas, orders and notifications may be made by mailing a copy by registered or certified mail to the person at its place of business or by handing a copy to a registered agent for service, or to any officer, director, or agent in charge of any office of such person, or by mailing a copy by registered or certified mail to such representative at his or her last known address, or by any other method whereby actual notice is given.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.14</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Witness fees and mileage (2 U.S.C. 437d(a)(5)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>Witnesses subpoenaed to appear for depositions shall be paid the same fees and mileage as witnesses in the courts of the United States. Such fees may be tendered at the time the witness appears for such deposition, or within a reasonable time thereafter.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.15</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Motions to quash or modify a subpoena (2 U.S.C. 437d(a) (3), (4)).</SUBJECT>

      <P>(a) Any person to whom a subpoena is directed may, prior to the time specified therein for compliance, but in no event more than 5 days after the date of receipt of such subpoena, apply to the Commission to quash or modify such subpoena, accompanying such application with a brief statement of the reasons therefor. Motions to quash shall be filed with the General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E <PRTPAGE P="144"/>Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463. If possible, three (3) copies should be submitted.</P>
      <P>(b) The Commission may deny the application or quash the subpoena or modify the subpoena.</P>
      <P>(c) The person subpoenaed and the General Counsel may agree to change the date, time, or place of a deposition or for the production of documents without affecting the force and effect of the subpoena, but such agreements shall be confirmed in writing.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15120, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.16</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The probable cause to believe recommendation; briefing procedures (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(3)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Upon completion of the investigation, the General Counsel shall prepare a brief setting forth his or her position on the factual and legal issues of the case and containing a recommendation on whether or not the Commission should find probable cause to believe that a violation has occurred or is about to occur.</P>
      <P>(b) The General Counsel shall notify each respondent of the recommendation and enclose a copy of his or her brief.</P>
      <P>(c) Within fifteen (15) days from receipt of the General Counsel's brief, respondent may file a brief with the Commission Secretary, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463, setting forth respondent's position on the factual and legal issues of the case. If possible, ten (10) copies of such brief should be filed with the Commission Secretary and three (3) copies should be submitted to the General Counsel, Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.</P>
      <P>(d) After reviewing the respondent's brief, the General Counsel shall advise the Commission in writing whether he or she intends to proceed with the recommendation or to withdraw the recommendation from Commission consideration.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15120, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.17</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>The probable cause to believe finding; notification (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) If the Commission, after having found reason to believe and after following the procedures set forth in 11 CFR 111.16, determines by an affirmative vote of four (4) of its members that there is probable cause to believe that a respondent has violated a statute or regulation over which the Commission has jurisdiction, the Commission shall authorize the General Counsel to so notify the respondent by letter.</P>
      <P>(b) If the Commission finds no probable cause to believe or otherwise orders a termination of Commission proceedings, it shall authorize the General Counsel to so notify both respondent and complainant by letter.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.18</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Conciliation (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Upon a Commission finding of probable cause to believe, the Office of General Counsel shall attempt to correct or prevent the violation by informal methods of conference conciliation and persuasion, and shall attempt to reach a tentative conciliation agreement with the respondent.</P>
      <P>(b) A conciliation agreement is not binding upon either party unless and until it is signed by the respondent and by the General Counsel upon approval by the affirmative vote of four (4) members of the Commission.</P>
      <P>(c) If the probable cause to believe finding is made within forty-five days prior to any election, such conciliation attempt shall continue for at least fifteen (15) days from the date of such finding. In all other cases such attempts by the Commission shall continue for at least thirty (30) days, not to exceed ninety (90) days.</P>

      <P>(d) Nothing in these regulations shall be construed to prevent the Commission from entering into a conciliation agreement with a respondent prior to a Commission finding of probable cause if a respondent indicates by letter to the General Counsel a desire to enter into negotiations directed towards reaching such a conciliation agreement. However, the Commission is not required to enter into any negotiations directed towards reaching a conciliation agreement unless and until it <PRTPAGE P="145"/>makes a finding of probable cause to believe. Any conciliation agreement reached under this subsection is subject to the provisions of subsection (b) of this section and shall have the same force and effect as a conciliation agreement reached after a Commission finding of probable cause to believe.</P>
      <P>(e) If a conciliation agreement is reached between the Commission and the respondent, the General Counsel shall send a copy of the signed agreement to both complainant and respondent.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.19</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Civil proceedings (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(6)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) If no conciliation agreement is finalized within the applicable minimum period specified by 11 CFR 111.18(c) the General Counsel may recommend to the Commission that the Commission authorize a civil action for relief in an appropriate court of the United States.</P>
      <P>(b) Upon recommendation of the General Counsel, the Commission may, by an affirmative vote of four (4) of its members, authorize the General Counsel to commence a civil action for relief in an appropriate court of the United States.</P>
      <P>(c) The provisions of 11 CFR 111.18(c) shall not preclude the Commission upon request of a respondent, from entering into a conciliation agreement even after a recommendation to file a civil action has been made pursuant to this section. Any conciliation agreement reached under this subsection is subject to the provisions of 11 CFR 111.18(b) and shall have the same force and effect as a conciliation agreement reached under 11 CFR 111.18(c).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.20</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Public disclosure of Commission action (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(4)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) If the Commission makes a finding of no reason to believe or no probable cause to believe or otherwise terminates its proceedings, it shall make public such action and the basis therefor no later than thirty (30) days from the date on which the required notifications are sent to complainant and respondent.</P>
      <P>(b) If a conciliation agreement is finalized, the Commission shall make public such conciliation agreement forthwith.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.21</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Confidentiality (2 U.S.C. 437g(a)(12)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) Except as provided in 11 CFR 111.20, no complaint filed with the Commission, nor any notification sent by the Commission, nor any investigation conducted by the Commission, nor any findings made by the Commission shall be made public by the Commission or by any person or entity without the written consent of the respondent with respect to whom the complaint was filed, the notification sent, the investigation conducted, or the finding made.</P>
      <P>(b) Except as provided in 11 CFR 111.20(b), no action by the Commission or by any person, and no information derived in connection with conciliation efforts pursuant to 11 CFR 111.18, may be made public by the Commission except upon a written request by respondent and approval thereof by the Commission.</P>
      <P>(c) Nothing in these regulations shall be construed to prevent the introduction of evidence in the courts of the United States which could properly be introduced pursuant to the Federal Rules of Evidence or Federal Rules of Civil Procedure.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.22</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Ex parte communications.</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) In order to avoid the possibility of prejudice, real or apparent, to the public interest in enforcement actions pending before the Commission pursuant to 11 CFR part 111, except to the extent required for the disposition of ex parte matters as required by law (for example, during the normal course of an investigation or a conciliation effort), no interested person outside the agency shall make or cause to be made to any Commissioner or any member of any Commissioner's staff any ex parte communication relative to the factual or legal merits of any enforcement action, nor shall any Commissioner or member of any Commissioner's staff make or entertain any such ex parte communications.</P>

      <P>(b) The prohibition of this regulation shall apply from the time a complaint is filed with the Commission pursuant to 11 CFR part 111 or from the time that the Commission determines on the basis of information ascertained in the <PRTPAGE P="146"/>normal course of its supervisory responsibilities that it has reason to believe that a violation has occurred or may occur pursuant to 11 CFR part 111, and remains in force until the Commission has finally concluded all action with respect to the enforcement matter in question.</P>
      <P>(c) Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit contact between a respondent or respondent's attorney and any attorney or staff member of the Office of General Counsel in the course of representing the Commission or the respondent with respect to an enforcement proceeding or civil action. No statement made by such a Commission attorney or staff member during any such communication shall bind or estop the Commission in any way.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 111.23</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Representation by counsel; notification.</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) If a respondent wishes to be represented by counsel with regard to any matter pending before the Commission, respondent shall so advise the Commission by sending a letter of representation signed by the respondent, which letter shall state the following:</P>
      <P>(1) The name, address, and telephone number of the counsel;</P>
      <P>(2) A statement authorizing such counsel to receive any and all notifications and other communications from the Commission on behalf of respondent.</P>
      <P>(b) Upon receipt of a letter of representation, the Commission shall have no contact with respondent except through the designated counsel unless authorized in writing by respondent.</P>
    </SECTION>
  </PART>
</CFRGRANULE>
