<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="cfr.xsl"?>
<CFRGRANULE xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="CFRMergedXML.xsd">
  <FDSYS>
    <CFRTITLE>11</CFRTITLE>
    <CFRTITLETEXT>Federal Elections</CFRTITLETEXT>
    <VOL>1</VOL>
    <DATE>1997-01-01</DATE>
    <ORIGINALDATE>1997-01-01</ORIGINALDATE>
    <COVERONLY>false</COVERONLY>
    <TITLE>SCOPE AND DEFINITIONS (2 U.S.C. 431)</TITLE>
    <GRANULENUM>100</GRANULENUM>
    <HEADING>PART 100</HEADING>
    <ANCESTORS>
      <PARENT HEADING="" SEQ="2"/>
      <PARENT HEADING="" SEQ="1"/>
      <PARENT HEADING="SUBCHAPTER A" SEQ="0">GENERAL</PARENT>
    </ANCESTORS>
  </FDSYS>
  <PART>
    <HD SOURCE="HED">PART 100—SCOPE AND DEFINITIONS (2 U.S.C. 431)</HD>
    <CONTENTS>
      <SECHD>Sec.</SECHD>
      <SECTNO>100.1</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Scope.</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.2</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Election (2 U.S.C. 431(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.3</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Candidate (2 U.S.C. 431(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.4</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Federal office (2 U.S.C. 431(3)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.5</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Political committee (2 U.S.C. 431 (4), (5), (6)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.6</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Connected organization (2 U.S.C. 431(7)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.7</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Contribution (2 U.S.C. 431(8)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.8</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Expenditure (2 U.S.C. 431(9)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.9</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Commission (2 U.S.C. 431(10)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.10</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Person (2 U.S.C. 431(11)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.11</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>State (2 U.S.C. 431(12)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.12</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Identification (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.13</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>National committee (2 U.S.C. 431(14)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.14</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>State committee, subordinate committee (2 U.S.C. 431(15)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.15</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Political party (2 U.S.C. 431(16)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.16</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Independent expenditure (2 U.S.C. 431(17)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.17</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Clearly identified (2 U.S.C. 431(18)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.18</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Act (2 U.S.C. 431(19)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.19</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>File, filed or filing (2 U.S.C. 434(a)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.20</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Occupation (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.21</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Employer (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <SECTNO>100.22</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Expressly advocating (2 U.S.C. 431(17)).</SUBJECT>
    </CONTENTS>
    <AUTH>
      <HD SOURCE="HED">Authority: </HD>
      <P>2 U.S.C. 431, 438(a)(8).</P>
    </AUTH>
    <SOURCE>
      <HD SOURCE="HED">Source: </HD>
      <P>45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980, unless otherwise noted.</P>
    </SOURCE>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.1</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Scope.</SUBJECT>
      <P>This subchapter is issued by the Federal Election Commission to implement the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (Pub. L. 92-225), as amended by Public Law 93-443, Public Law 94-283, Public Law 95-216, and Public Law 96-187.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.2</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Election (2 U.S.C. 431(1)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) <E T="03">Election</E> means the process by which individuals, whether opposed or unopposed, seek nomination for election, or election, to Federal office. The specific types of elections, as set forth at 11 CFR 100.2(b), (c), (d), (e) and (f) are included in this definition.</P>
      <P>(b) <E T="03">General election.</E> A general election is an election which meets either of the following conditions:</P>
      <P>(1) An election held in even numbered years on the Tuesday following the first Monday in November is a general election.</P>
      <P>(2) An election which is held to fill a vacancy in a Federal office (i.e., a special election) and which is intended to result in the final selection of a single individual to the office at stake is a general election. See 11 CFR 100.2(f).</P>
      <P>(c) <E T="03">Primary election.</E> A primary election is an election which meets one of the following conditions:</P>
      <P>(1) An election which is held prior to a general election, as a direct result of which candidates are nominated, in accordance with applicable State law, for election to Federal office in a subsequent election is a primary election.</P>
      <P>(2) An election which is held for the expression of a preference for the nomination of persons for election to the office of President of the United States is a primary election.</P>
      <P>(3) An election which is held to elect delegates to a national nominating convention is a primary election.</P>
      <P>(4) With respect to individuals seeking federal office as independent candidates, or without nomination by a major party (as defined in 26 U.S.C. 9002(6)), the primary election is considered to occur on one of the following dates, at the choice of the candidate:</P>
      <P>(i) The day prescribed by applicable State law as the last day to qualify for a position on the general election ballot may be designated as the primary election for such candidate.</P>
      <P>(ii) The date of the last major party primary election, caucus, or convention in that State may be designated as the primary election for such candidate.</P>
      <P>(iii) In the case of non-major parties, the date of the nomination by that party may be designated as the primary election for such candidate.</P>

      <P>(5) With respect to any major party candidate (as defined at 26 U.S.C. 9002(6)) who is unopposed for nomination within his or her own party, and who is certified to appear as that party's nominee in the general election for the office sought, the primary election is considered to have occurred on the date on which the primary election was <PRTPAGE P="47"/>held by the candidate's party in that State.</P>
      <P>(d) <E T="03">Runoff election. Runoff election</E> means the election which meets either of the following conditions:</P>
      <P>(1) The election held after a primary election, and prescribed by applicable State law as the means for deciding which candidate(s) should be certified as a nominee for the Federal office sought, is a runoff election.</P>
      <P>(2) The election held after a general election and prescribed by applicable State law as the means for deciding which candidate should be certified as an officeholder elect, is a runoff election.</P>
      <P>(e) <E T="03">Caucus or Convention.</E> A caucus or convention of a political party is an election if the caucus or convention has the authority to select a nominee for federal office on behalf of that party.</P>
      <P>(f) <E T="03">Special election. Special election</E> means an election which is held to fill a vacancy in a Federal office. A special election may be a primary, general, or runoff election, as defined at 11 CFR 100.2(b), (c) and (d).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.3</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Candidate (2 U.S.C. 431(2)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) <E T="03">Definition. Candidate</E> means an individual who seeks nomination for election, or election, to federal office. An individual becomes a candidate for Federal office whenever any of the following events occur:</P>
      <P>(1) The individual has received contributions aggregating in excess of $5,000 or made expenditures aggregating in excess of $5,000.</P>
      <P>(2) The individual has given his or her consent to another person to receive contributions or make expenditures on behalf of that individual and such person has received contributions aggregating in excess of $5,000 or made expenditures aggregating in excess of $5,000.</P>
      <P>(3) After written notification by the Commission that any other person has received contributions aggregating in excess of $5,000 or made expenditures aggregating in excess of $5,000 on the individual's behalf, the individual fails to disavow such activity by letter to the Commission within 30 days of receipt of the notification.</P>
      <P>(4) The aggregate of contributions received under 11 CFR 100.3(a) (1), (2), and (3), in any combination thereof, exceeds $5,000, or the aggregate of expenditures made under 11 CFR 100.3(a) (1), (2), and (3), in any combination thereof, exceeds $5,000.</P>
      <P>(b) <E T="03">Election cycle.</E> For purposes of determining whether an individual is a candidate under this section, contributions or expenditures shall be aggregated on an election cycle basis. An election cycle shall begin on the first day following the date of the previous general election for the office or seat which the candidate seeks, unless contributions or expenditures are designated for another election cycle. For an individual who receives contributions or makes expenditures designated for another election cycle, the election cycle shall begin at the time such individual, or any other person acting on the individual's behalf, first receives contributions or makes expenditures in connection with the designated election. The election cycle shall end on the date on which the general election for the office or seat that the individual seeks is held.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.4</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Federal office (2 U.S.C. 431(3)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Federal office</E> means the office of President or Vice President of the United States, Senator or Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress of the United States.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.5</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Political committee (2 U.S.C. 431 (4), (5), (6)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Political committee</E> means any group meeting one of the following conditions:</P>
      <P>(a) Except as provided in 11 CFR 100.5(b), (c) and (d), any committee, club, association, or other group of persons which receives contributions aggregating in excess of $1,000 or which makes expenditures aggregating in excess of $1,000 during a calendar year is a political committee.</P>
      <P>(b) Any separate segregated fund established under 2 U.S.C. 441b(b)(2)(C) is a political committee.</P>

      <P>(c) Any local committee of a political party is a political committee if: it receives contributions aggregating in excess of $5,000 during a calendar year; it <PRTPAGE P="48"/>makes payments exempted from the definition of contribution, under 11 CFR 100.7(b)(9), (15) and (17), and expenditure, under 11 CFR 100.8(b)(10), (16) and (18), which payments aggregate in excess of $5,000 during a calendar year; or it makes contributions aggregating in excess of $1,000 or makes expenditures aggregating in excess of $1,000 during a calendar year.</P>
      <P>(d) An individual's principal campaign committee or authorized committee(s) becomes a political committee(s) when that individual becomes a candidate pursuant to 11 CFR 100.3.</P>
      <P>(e) The following are examples of political committees:</P>
      <P>(1) <E T="03">Principal campaign committee. Principal campaign committee</E> means a political committee designated and authorized by a candidate pursuant to 11 CFR 101.1 and 102.1.</P>
      <P>(2) <E T="03">Single candidate committee. Single candidate committee</E> means a political committee other than a principal campaign committee which makes or receives contributions or makes expenditures on behalf of only one candidate.</P>
      <P>(3) <E T="03">Multi-candidate committee. Multi-candidate committee</E> means a political committee which (i) has been registered with the Commission or Secretary of the Senate for at least 6 months; (ii) has received contributions for Federal elections from more than 50 persons; and (iii) (except for any State political party organization) has made contributions to 5 or more Federal candidates.</P>
      <P>(4) <E T="03">Party committee. Party committee</E> means a political committee which represents a political party and is part of the official party structure at the national, State, or local level.</P>
      <P>(5) <E T="03">Delegate committee.</E> A delegate committee is a group of persons that receives contributions or makes expenditures for the sole purpose of influencing the selection of one or more delegates to a national nominating convention. The term <E T="03">delegate committee</E> includes a group of delegates, a group of individuals seeking selection as delegates and a group of individuals supporting delegates. A delegate committee that qualifies as a political committee under 11 CFR 100.5 must register with the Commission pursuant to 11 CFR part 102 and report its receipts and disbursements in accordance with 11 CFR part 104. (See definition of <E T="03">delegate</E> at 11 CFR 110.14(b)(1).)</P>
      <P>(f) A political committee is either an authorized committee or an unauthorized committee.</P>
      <P>(1) <E T="03">Authorized committee.</E> An <E T="03">authorized committee</E> means the principal campaign committee or any other political committee authorized by a candidate under 11 CFR 102.13 to receive contributions or make expenditures on behalf of such candidate, or which has not been disavowed pursuant to 11 CFR 100.3(a)(3).</P>
      <P>(2) <E T="03">Unauthorized committee.</E> An <E T="03">unauthorized committee</E> is a political committee which has not been authorized in writing by a candidate to solicit or receive contributions or make expenditures on behalf of such candidate, or which has been disavowed pursuant to 11 CFR 100.3(a)(3).</P>
      <P>(g) <E T="03">Affiliated committee.</E> (1) All authorized committees of the same candidate for the same election to Federal office are affiliated.</P>
      <P>(2) All committees (including a separate segregated fund, <E T="03">see</E> 11 CFR part 114) established, financed, maintained or controlled by the same corporation, labor organization, person, or group of persons, including any parent, subsidiary, branch, division, department, or local unit thereof, are affiliated. <E T="03">Local unit</E> may include, in appropriate cases, a franchisee, licensee, or State or regional association.</P>
      <P>(3) Affiliated committees sharing a single contribution limitation under paragraph (g)(2) of this section include all of the committees established, financed, maintained or controlled by—I11(i) A single corporation and/or its subsidiaries;</P>
      <P>(ii) A single national or international union and/or its local unions or other subordinate organizations;</P>
      <P>(iii) An organization of national or international unions and/or all its State and local central bodies;</P>

      <P>(iv) A membership organization, (other than political party committees, <E T="03">see</E> 11 CFR 110.3(b)) including trade or professional associations, <E T="03">see</E> 11 CFR 114.8(a), and/or related State and local entities of that organization or group; or<PRTPAGE P="49"/>
      </P>
      <P>(v) The same person or group of persons.</P>
      <P>(4)(i) The Commission may examine the relationship between organizations that sponsor committees, between the committees themselves, or between one sponsoring organization and a committee established by another organization to determine whether committees are affiliated.</P>
      <P>(ii) In determining whether committees not described in paragraphs (g)(3) (i)-(iv) of this section are affiliated, the Commission will consider the circumstantial factors described in paragraphs (g)(4)(ii) (A) through (J) of this section. The Commission will examine these factors in the context of the overall relationship between committees or sponsoring organizations to determine whether the presence of any factor or factors is evidence of one committee or organization having been established, financed, maintained or controlled by another committee or sponsoring organization. Such factors include, but are not limited to:</P>
      <P>(A) Whether a sponsoring organization owns controlling interest in the voting stock or securities of the sponsoring organization of another committee;</P>
      <P>(B) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee has the authority or ability to direct or participate in the governance of another sponsoring organization or committee through provisions of constitutions, bylaws, contracts, or other rules, or through formal or informal practices or procedures;</P>
      <P>(C) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee has the authority or ability to hire, appoint, demote or otherwise control the officers, or other decisionmaking employees or members of another sponsoring organization or committee;</P>
      <P>(D) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee has a common or overlapping membership with another sponsoring organization or committee which indicates a formal or ongoing relationship between the sponsoring organizations or committees;</P>
      <P>(E) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee has common or overlapping officers or employees with another sponsoring organization or committee which indicates a formal or ongoing relationship between the sponsoring organizations or committees;</P>
      <P>(F) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee has any members, officers or employees who were members, officers or employees of another sponsoring organization or committee which indicates a formal or ongoing relationship between the sponsoring organizations or committees, or which indicates the creation of a successor entity;</P>
      <P>(G) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee provides funds or goods in a significant amount or on an ongoing basis to another sponsoring organization or committee, such as through direct or indirect payments for administrative, fundraising, or other costs, but not including the transfer to a committee of its allocated share of proceeds jointly raised pursuant to 11 CFR 102.17;</P>
      <P>(H) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee causes or arranges for funds in a significant amount or on an ongoing basis to be provided to another sponsoring organization or committee, but not including the transfer to a committee of its allocated share of proceeds jointly raised pursuant to 11 CFR 102.17;</P>
      <P>(I) Whether a sponsoring organization or committee or its agent had an active or significant role in the formation of another sponsoring organization or committee; and</P>
      <P>(J) Whether the sponsoring organizations or committees have similar patterns of contributions or contributors which indicates a formal or ongoing relationship between the sponsoring organizations or committees.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 45 FR 34867, May 23, 1980; 52 FR 35534, Sept. 22, 1987; 54 FR 34109, Aug. 17, 1989; 54 FR 48580, Nov. 24, 1989; 61 FR 3549, Feb. 1, 1996]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.6</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Connected organization (2 U.S.C. 431(7)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) <E T="03">Connected organization</E> means any organization which is not a political committee but which directly or indirectly establishes, administers, or financially supports a political committee. A connected organization may be a corporation (including a corporation <PRTPAGE P="50"/>without capital stock), a labor organization, a membership organization, a cooperative or a trade association.</P>
      <P>(b) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.6, organizations which are members of the entity (such as corporate members of a trade association) which establishes, administers, or financially supports a political committee are not organizations which directly or indirectly establish, administer or financially support that political committee.</P>
      <P>(c) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.6, the term <E T="03">financially supports</E> does not include contributions to the political committee, but does include the payment of establishment, administration and solicitation costs of such committee.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.7</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Contribution (2 U.S.C. 431(8)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) The term <E T="03">contribution</E> includes the following payments, services or other things of value:</P>
      <P>(1) A gift, subscription, loan (except for a loan made in accordance with 11 CFR 100.7(b)(11)), advance, or deposit of money or anything of value made by any person for the purpose of influencing any election for Federal office is a contribution.</P>
      <P>(i) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1), the term <E T="03">loan</E> includes a guarantee, endorsement, and any other form of security.</P>
      <P>(A) A loan which exceeds the contribution limitations of 2 U.S.C. 441a and 11 CFR part 110 shall be unlawful whether or not it is repaid.</P>
      <P>(B) A loan is a contribution at the time it is made and is a contribution to the extent that it remains unpaid. The aggregate amount loaned to a candidate or committee by a contributor, when added to other contributions from that individual to that candidate or committee, shall not exceed the contribution limitations set forth at 11 CFR part 110. A loan, to the extent it is repaid, is no longer a contribution.</P>
      <P>(C) Except as provided in (D), a loan is a contribution by each endorser or guarantor. Each endorser or guarantor shall be deemed to have contributed that portion of the total amount of the loan for which he or she agreed to be liable in a written agreement. Any reduction in the unpaid balance of the loan shall reduce proportionately the amount endorsed or guaranteed by each endorser or guarantor in such written agreement. In the event that such agreement does not stipulate the portion of the loan for which each endorser or guarantor is liable, the loan shall be considered a loan by each endorser or guarantor in the same proportion to the unpaid balance that each endorser or guarantor bears to the total number of endorsers or guarantors.</P>
      <P>(D) A candidate may obtain a loan on which his or her spouse's signature is required when jointly owned assets are used as collateral or security for the loan. The spouse shall not be considered a contributor to the candidate's campaign if the value of the candidate's share of the property used as collateral equals or exceeds the amount of the loan which is used for the candidate's campaign.</P>
      <P>(E) If a political committee makes a loan to any person, such loan shall be subject to the limitations of 11 CFR part 110. Repayment of the principal amount of such loan to such political committee shall not be a contribution by the debtor to the lender committee. Such repayment shall be made with funds which are subject to the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4(a) and part 114. The payment of interest to such committee by the debtor shall be a contribution only to the extent that the interest paid exceeds a commercially reasonable rate prevailing at the time the loan is made. All payments of interest shall be made from funds subject to the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4(a) and part 114.</P>
      <P>(ii) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1), the term <E T="03">money</E> includes currency of the United States or of any foreign nation, checks, money orders, or any other negotiable instruments payable on demand.</P>
      <P>(iii) (A) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1), the term <E T="03">anything of value</E> includes all in-kind contributions. Unless specifically exempted under 11 CFR 100.7(b), the provision of any goods or services without charge or at a charge which is less than the usual and normal charge for such goods or services is a contribution. Examples of such goods or services include, but are not limited to: Securities, facilities, <PRTPAGE P="51"/>equipment, supplies, personnel, advertising services, membership lists, and mailing lists. If goods or services are provided at less than the usual and normal charge, the amount of the in-kind contribution is the difference between the usual and normal charge for the goods or services at the time of the contribution and the amount charged the political committee.</P>
      <P>(B) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1)(iii)(A), <E T="03">usual and normal charge</E> for goods means the price of those goods in the market from which they ordinarily would have been purchased at the time of the contribution; and <E T="03">usual and normal charge</E> for any services, other than those provided by an unpaid volunteer, means the hourly or piecework charge for the services at a commercially reasonable rate prevailing at the time the services were rendered.</P>
      <P>(2) The entire amount paid to attend a fundraiser or other political event and the entire amount paid as the purchase price for a fundraising item sold by a political committee is a contribution.</P>
      <P>(3) The payment by any person of compensation for the personal services of another person if those services are rendered without charge to a political committee for any purpose, except for legal and accounting services provided under 11 CFR 100.7(b)(13) or (14), is a contribution. No compensation is considered paid to any employee under any of the following conditions:</P>
      <P>(i) If an employee is paid on an hourly or salaried basis and is expected to work a particular number of hours per period, no contribution results if the employee engages in political activity during what would otherwise be a regular work period, provided that the taken or released time is made up or completed by the employee within a reasonable time.</P>
      <P>(ii) No contribution results where an employee engages in political activity during what would otherwise be normal working hours if the employee is paid on a commission or piecework basis, or is paid only for work actually performed and the employee's time is considered his or her own to use as he or she sees fit.</P>
      <P>(iii) No contribution results where the time used by the employee to engage in political activity is bona fide, although compensable, vacation time or other earned leave time.</P>

      <P>(4) The extension of credit by any person is a contribution unless the credit is extended in the ordinary course of the person's business and the terms are substantially similar to extensions of credit to nonpolitical debtors that are of similar risk and size of obligation. If a creditor fails to make a commercially reasonable attempt to collect the debt, a contribution will result. (<E T="03">See</E> 11 CFR 116.3 and 116.4.) If a debt owed by a political committee is forgiven or settled for less than the amount owed, a contribution results unless such debt is settled in accordance with the standards set forth at 11 CFR 116.3 and 116.4.</P>
      <P>(b) The term <E T="03">contribution</E> does not include the following payments, services or other things of value:</P>
      <P>(1) (i) Funds received solely for the purpose of determining whether an individual should become a candidate are not contributions. Examples of activities permissible under this exemption if they are conducted to determine whether an individual should become a candidate include, but are not limited to, conducting a poll, telephone calls, and travel. Only funds permissible under the Act may be used for such activities. The individual shall keep records of all such funds received. See 11 CFR 101.3. If the individual subsequently becomes a candidate, the funds received are contributions subject to the reporting requirements of the Act. Such contributions must be reported with the first report filed by the principal campaign committee of the candidate, regardless of the date the funds were received.</P>
      <P>ii) This exemption does not apply to funds received for activities indicating that an individual has decided to become a candidate for a particular office or for activities relevant to conducting a campaign. Examples of activities that indicate that an individual has decided to become a candidate include, but are not limited to:</P>

      <P>(A) The individual uses general public political advertising to publicize his <PRTPAGE P="52"/>or her intention to campaign for Federal office.</P>
      <P>(B) The individual raises funds in excess of what could reasonably be expected to be used for exploratory activities or undertakes activities designed to amass campaign funds that would be spent after he or she becomes a candidate.</P>
      <P>(C) The individual makes or authorizes written or oral statements that refer to him or her as a candidate for a particular office.</P>
      <P>(D) The individual conducts activities in close proximity to the election or over a protracted period of time.</P>
      <P>(E) The individual has taken action to qualify for the ballot under State law.</P>

      <P>(2) Any cost incurred in covering or carrying a news story, commentary, or editorial by any broadcasting station (including a cable television operator, programmer or producer), newspaper, magazine, or other periodical publication is not a contribution unless the facility is owned or controlled by any political party, political committee, or candidate, in which case the costs for a news story (i) which represents a <E T="03">bona fide</E> news account communicated in a publication of general circulation or on a licensed broadcasting facility, and (ii) which is part of a general pattern of campaign-related news accounts which give reasonably equal coverage to all opposing candidates in the circulation or listening area, is not a contribution.</P>
      <P>(3) The value of services provided without compensation by any individual who volunteers on behalf of a candidate or political committee is not a contribution.</P>
      <P>(4) No contribution results where an individual, in the course of volunteering personal services on his or her residential premises to any candidate or to any political committee of a political party, provides the use of his or her real or personal property to such candidate for candidate-related activity or to such political committee of a political party for party-related activity. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(4), an individual's residential premises, shall include a recreation room in a residential complex where the individual volunteering services resides, provided that the room is available for use without regard to political affiliation. A nominal fee paid by such individual for the use of such room is not a contribution.</P>
      <P>(5) No contribution results where an individual, in the course of volunteering personal services to any candidate or political committee of a political party, obtains the use of a church or community room and provides such room to any candidate for candidate-related activity or to any political committee of a political party for party-related activity, provided that the room is used on a regular basis by members of the community for noncommercial purposes and the room is available for use by members of the community without regard to political affiliation. A nominal fee paid by such individual for the use of such room is not a contribution.</P>
      <P>(6) The cost of invitations, food and beverages is not a contribution where such items are voluntarily provided by an individual volunteering personal services on the individual's residential premises or in a church or community room as specified at 11 CFR 100.7(b)(4) and (5) to a candidate for candidate-related activity or to any political committee of a political party for party-related activity, to the extent that: The aggregate value of such invitations, food and beverages provided by the individual on behalf of the candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to any single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in any calendar year.</P>

      <P>(7) The sale of any food or beverage by a vendor (whether incorporated or not) for use in a candidate's campaign, or for use by a political committee of a political party, at a charge less than the normal or comparable commercial rate, is not a contribution, provided that the charge is at least equal to the cost of such food or beverage to the vendor, to the extent that: The aggregate value of such discount given by the vendor on behalf of any single candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to any single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in a calendar year.<PRTPAGE P="53"/>
      </P>
      <P>(8) Any unreimbursed payment for transportation expenses incurred by any individual on behalf of any candidate or any political committee of a political party is not a contribution to the extent that: The aggregate value of the payments made by such individual on behalf of a candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to a single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in a calendar year. Additionally, any unreimbursed payment from a volunteer's personal funds for usual and normal subsistence expenses incidental to volunteer activity is not a contribution.</P>
      <P>(9) The payment by a State or local committee of a political party of the costs of preparation, display, or mailing or other distribution incurred by such committee with respect to a printed slate card, sample ballot, palm card, or other printed listing(s) of three or more candidates for any public office for which an election is held in the State in which the committee is organized is not a contribution. The payment of the portion of such costs allocable to Federal candidates must be made from funds subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act. If made by a political committee, such payments shall be reported by that committee as disbursements, but need not be allocated in committee reports to specific candidates. This exemption shall not apply to costs incurred by such a committee with respect to the preparation and display of listings made on broadcasting stations, or in newspapers, magazines, and similar types of general public political advertising such as billboards.</P>
      <P>(10) Any payment made or obligation incurred by a corporation or a labor organization is not a contribution if under the provisions of 11 CFR part 114 such payment or obligation would not constitute an expenditure by the corporation or labor organization.</P>
      <P>(11) A loan of money by a State bank, a federally chartered depository institution (including a national bank) or a depository institution whose deposits and accounts are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration is not a contribution by the lending institution if such loan is made in accordance with applicable banking laws and regulations and is made in the ordinary course of business. A loan will be deemed to be made in the ordinary course of business if it: Bears the usual and customary interest rate of the lending institution for the category of loan involved; is made on a basis which assures repayment; is evidenced by a written instrument; and is subject to a due date or amortization schedule. Such loans shall be reported by the political committee in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(a). Each endorser or guarantor shall be deemed to have contributed that portion of the total amount of the loan for which he or she agreed to be liable in a written agreement, except that, in the event of a signature by the candidate's spouse, the provisions of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1)(i)(D) shall apply. Any reduction in the unpaid balance of the loan shall reduce proportionately the amount endorsed or guaranteed by each endorser or guarantor in such written agreement. In the event that such agreement does not stipulate the portion of the loan for which each endorser or guarantor is liable, the loan shall be considered a contribution by each endorser or guarantor in the same proportion to the unpaid balance that each endorser or guarantor bears to the total number of endorsers or guarantors. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(11), an overdraft made on a checking or savings account shall be considered a contribution by the bank or institution unless: The overdraft is made on an account which is subject to automatic overdraft protection; the overdraft is subject to a definite interest rate which is usual and customary; and there is a definite repayment schedule.</P>

      <P>(i) A loan, including a line of credit, shall be considered made on a basis which assures repayment if it is obtained using either of the sources of repayment described in paragraphs (b)(11)(i) (A) or (B) of this section, or a combination of paragraphs (b)(11)(i) (A) and (B) of this section:<PRTPAGE P="54"/>
      </P>
      <P>(A)(<E T="03">1</E>) The lending institution making the loan has perfected a security interest in collateral owned by the candidate or political committee receiving the loan, the fair market value of the collateral is equal to or greater than the loan amount and any senior liens as determined on the date of the loan, and the candidate or political committee provides documentation to show that the lending institution has a perfected security interest in the collateral. Sources of collateral include, but are not limited to, ownership in real estate, personal property, goods, negotiable instruments, certificates of deposit, chattel papers, stocks, accounts receivable and cash on deposit.</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Amounts guaranteed by secondary sources of repayment, such as guarantors and cosigners, shall not exceed the contribution limits of 11 CFR part 110 or contravene the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4, part 114 and part 115; or</P>

      <P>(B) The lending institution making the loan has obtained a written agreement whereby the candidate or political committee receiving the loan has pledged future receipts, such as public financing payments under 11 CFR part 9001 <E T="03">et seq.</E> or part 9031 <E T="03">et seq.</E>, contributions, or interest income, provided that:</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) The amount of the loan or loans obtained on the basis of such funds does not exceed the amount of pledged funds;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Loan amounts are based on a reasonable expectation of the receipt of pledged funds. To that end, the candidate or political committee must furnish the lending institution documentation, i.e., cash flow charts or other financial plans, that reasonably establish that such future funds will be available;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">3</E>) A separate depository account is established at the lending institution or the lender obtains an assignment from the candidate or political committee to access funds in a committee account at another depository institution that meets the requirements of 11 CFR 103.2, and the committee has notified the other institution of this assignment;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">4</E>) The loan agreement requires the deposit of the public financing payments, contributions and interest income pledged as collateral into the separate depository account for the purpose of retiring the debt according to the repayment requirements of the loan agreement; and</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">5</E>) In the case of public financing payments, the borrower authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to directly deposit the payments into the depository account for the purpose of retiring the debt.</P>
      <P>(ii) If the requirements set forth in paragraph (b)(11)(i) of this section are not met, the Commission will consider the totality of the circumstances on a case-by-case basis in determining whether a loan was made on a basis which assures repayment.</P>
      <P>(12) A gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value made to a national committee or a State committee of a political party is not a contribution if it is specifically designated to defray any cost incurred for construction or purchase of any office facility which is not acquired for the purpose of influencing the election of any candidate in any particular election for Federal office. If such gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value is made to a committee which is not a political committee under 11 CFR 100.5, the amount need not be reported. However, if such gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value is made to a political committee, it shall be reported in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(g).</P>
      <P>(13) Legal or accounting services rendered to or on behalf of any political committee of a political party are not contributions if the person paying for such services is the regular employer of the individual rendering the services and such services are not attributable to activities which directly further the election of any designated candidate for Federal office. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(13), a partnership shall be deemed to be the regular employer of a partner. Amounts paid by the regular employer for such services shall be reported by the committee receiving such services in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(h).</P>

      <P>(14) Legal or accounting services rendered to or on behalf of an authorized committee of a candidate or any other <PRTPAGE P="55"/>political committee are not contributions if the person paying for such services is the regular employer of the individual rendering the services and if such services are solely to ensure compliance with the Act or 26 U.S.C. 9001 <E T="03">et seq.</E> and 9031 <E T="03">et seq.</E> For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(14), a partnership shall be deemed to be the regular employer of a partner. Amounts paid by the regular employer for these services shall be reported by the committee receiving such services in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(h).</P>
      <P>(15) The payment by a state or local committee of a political party of the costs of campaign materials (such as pins, bumper stickers, handbills, brochures, posters, party tabloids or newletters, and yard signs) used by such committee in connection with volunteer activities on behalf of any nominee(s) of such party is not a contribution, provided that the following conditions are met:</P>

      <P>(i) Such payment is not for cost incurred in connection with any broadcasting, newspaper, magazine, bill board, direct mail, or similar type of general public communication or political advertising. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(15)(i), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means any mailing(s) by a commercial vendor or any mailing(s) made from commercial lists.</P>
      <P>(ii) The portion of the cost of such materials allocable to Federal candidates is paid from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act.</P>

      <P>(iii) Such payment is not made from contributions designated by the donor to be spent on behalf of a particular candidate or candidates for Federal office. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(15)(iii), a contribution shall not be considered a <E T="03">designated contribution</E> if the party committee disbursing the funds makes the final decision regarding which candidate(s) shall receive the benefit of such disbursement.</P>
      <P>(iv) Such materials are distributed by volunteers and not by commercial or for-profit operations. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(15)(iv), payments by the party organization for travel and subsistence or customary token payments to volunteers do not remove such individuals from the volunteer category.</P>
      <P>(v) If made by a political committee such payments shall be reported by the political committee as disbursements in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3 but need not be allocated to specific candidates in committee reports.</P>
      <P>(vi) Payments by a State candidate or his or her campaign committee to a State or local political party committee for the State candidate's share of expenses for such campaign materials are not contributions, provided the amount paid by the State candidate or his or her committee does not exceed his or her proportionate share of the expenses.</P>
      <P>(vii) Campaign materials purchased by the national committee of a political party and delivered to a State or local party committee, or materials purchased with funds donated by the national committee to such State or local committee for the purchase of such materials, shall not qualify under this exemption. Rather, the cost of such materials shall be subject to the limitations of 2 U.S.C. 441a(d) and 11 CFR 110.7.</P>

      <P>(16) The payment by a candidate for any public office (including State or local office), or by such candidate's authorized committee, of the costs of that candidate's campaign materials which include information on or any reference to a candidate for Federal office and which are used in connection with volunteer activities (such as pins, bumper stickers, handbills, brochures, posters, and yard signs) is not a contribution to such candidate for Federal office, provided that the payment is not for the use of broadcasting, newspapers, magazines, billboards, direct mail or similar types of general public communication or political advertising. The payment of the portion of the cost of such materials allocable to Federal candidates shall be made from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(16), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means any mailing(s) by commercial vendors or mailing(s) made from lists which were not developed by the candidate.</P>

      <P>(17) The payment by a State or local committee of a political party of the <PRTPAGE P="56"/>costs of voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities conducted by such committee on behalf of the Presidential and Vice Presidential nominee(s) of that party, is not a contribution to such candidate(s) provided that the following conditions are met:</P>

      <P>(i) Such payment is not for the costs incurred in connection with any broadcasting, newspaper, magazine, billboard, direct mail, or similar type of general public communication or political advertising. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(17)(i), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means any mailing(s) by a commercial vendor or any mailing(s) made from commercial lists.</P>
      <P>(ii) The portion of the costs of such activities allocable to Federal candidates is paid from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act.</P>

      <P>(iii) Such payment is not made from contributions designated to be spent on behalf of a particular candidate or candidates for Federal office. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(17)(iii), a contribution shall not be considered a <E T="03">designated contribution</E> if the party committee disbursing the funds makes the final decision regarding which candidate(s) shall receive the benefit of such disbursement.</P>
      <P>(iv) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(17), if such activities include references to any candidate(s) for the House or Senate, the costs of such activities which are allocable to that candidate(s) shall be a contribution to such candidate(s) unless the mention of such candidate(s) is merely incidental to the overall activity.</P>
      <P>(v) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(b)(17), payment of the costs incurred in the use of phone banks in connection with voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities is not a contribution when such phone banks are operated by volunteer workers. The use of paid professionals to design the phone bank system, develop calling instructions and train supervisors is permissible. The payment of the costs of such professional services is not an expenditure but shall be reported as a disbursement in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3 if made by a political committee.</P>
      <P>(vi) If made by a political committee, such payments for voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities shall be reported by that committee as disbursements in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3, but such payments need not be allocated to specific candidates in committee reports except as provided in 11 CFR 100.7(b)(17)(iv).</P>
      <P>(vii) Payments made from funds donated by a national committee of a political party to a State or local party committee for voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities shall not qualify under this exemption. Rather, such funds shall be subject to the limitations of 2 U.S.C. 441a(d) and 11 CFR 110.7.</P>
      <P>(18) Payments made to any party committee by a candidate or the authorized committee of a candidate as a condition of ballot access are not contributions.</P>
      <P>(19) [Reserved]</P>
      <P>(20) A gift, subscription, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value made with respect to a recount of the results of a Federal election, or an election contest concerning a Federal election, is not a contribution except that the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4(a) and part 114 apply.</P>
      <P>(21) Funds provided to defray costs incurred in staging candidate debates in accordance with the provisions of 11 CFR 110.13 and 114.4(f).</P>
      <P>(c) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.7(a) and (b), a contribution or payment made by an individual shall not be attributed to any other individual, unless otherwise specified by that other individual in accordance with 11 CFR 110.1(k).</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 45 FR 21209, Apr. 1, 1980; 45 FR 23642, Apr. 8, 1980; 48 FR 19020, Apr. 27, 1983; 50 FR 9994, Mar. 13, 1985; 52 FR 773, Jan. 9, 1987; 55 FR 26385, June 27, 1990; 56 FR 67123, Dec. 27, 1991; 57 FR 1640, Jan. 15, 1992; 60 FR 64272, Dec. 14, 1995; 61 FR 18051, Apr. 24, 1996]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.8</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Expenditure (2 U.S.C. 431(9)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) The term <E T="03">expenditure</E> incudes the following payments, gifts or other things of value:</P>

      <P>(1) A purchase, payment, distribution, loan (except for a loan made in accordance with 11 CFR 100.8(b)(12)), advance, deposit, or gift of money or <PRTPAGE P="57"/>anything of value, made by any person for the purpose of influencing any election for Federal office is an expenditure.</P>
      <P>(i) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a)(1), the term <E T="03">payment</E> includes payment of any interest on an obligation and any guarantee or endorsement of a loan by a candidate or a political committee.</P>
      <P>(ii) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a)(1), the term <E T="03">payment</E> does not include the repayment by a political committee of the principal of an outstanding obligation which is owed by such committee, except that the repayment shall be reported as disbursements in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(b).</P>
      <P>(iii) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a)(1), the term <E T="03">money</E> includes currency of the United States or of any foreign nation, checks, money orders, or any other negotiable instrument payable on demand.</P>
      <P>(iv)(A) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a)(1), the term <E T="03">anything of value</E> includes all in-kind contributions. Unless specifically exempted under 11 CFR 100.8(b), the provision of any goods or services without charge or at a charge which is less than the usual and normal charge for the goods or services is an expenditure. Examples of such goods or services include, but are not limited to: Securities, facilities, equipment, supplies, personnel, advertising services, membership lists, and mailing lists. If goods or services are provided at less than the usual and normal charge, the amount of the expenditure is the difference between the usual and normal charge for the goods or services at the time of the expenditure and the amount charged the candidate or political committee.</P>
      <P>(B) For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a)(1)(iv)(A), <E T="03">usual and normal charge</E> for goods means the price of those goods in the market from which they ordinarily would have been purchased at the time of the expenditure; and <E T="03">usual and normal charge</E> for services, other than those provided by an unpaid volunteer, means the hourly or piecework charge for the services at a commerically reasonable rate prevailing at the time the services were rendered.</P>
      <P>(2) A written contract, including a media contract, promise, or agreement to make an expenditure is an expenditure as of the date such contract, promise or obligation is made.</P>
      <P>(3) An independent expenditure which meets the requirements of 11 CFR 104.4 or part 109 is an expenditure, and such independent expenditure is to be reported by the person making the expenditure in accordance with 11 CFR 104.4 and part 109.</P>
      <P>(b) The term <E T="03">expenditure</E> does not include the following payments, gifts, or other things of value:</P>
      <P>(1) (i) Payments made solely for the purpose of determining whether an individual should become a candidate are not expenditures. Examples of activities permissible under this exemption if they are conducted to determine whether an individual should become a candidate include, but are not limited to, conducting a poll, telephone calls, and travel. Only funds permissible under the Act may be used for such activities. The individual shall keep records of all such payments. See 11 CFR 101.3. If the individual subsequently becomes a candidate, the payments made are subject to the reporting requirements of the Act. Such expenditures must be reported with the first report filed by the principal campaign committee of the candidate, regardless of the date the payments were made.</P>
      <P>(ii) This exemption does not apply to payments made for activities indicating that an individual has decided to become a candidate for a particular office or for activities relevant to conducting a campaign. Examples of activities that indicate that an individual has decided to become a candidate include, but are not limited to:</P>
      <P>(A) The individual uses general public political advertising to publicize his or her intention to campaign for Federal office.</P>
      <P>(B) The individual raises funds in excess of what could reasonably be expected to be used for exploratory activities or undertakes activities designed to amass campaign funds that would be spent after he or she becomes a candidate.</P>

      <P>(C) The individual makes or authorizes written or oral statements that refer to him or her as a candidate for a particular office.<PRTPAGE P="58"/>
      </P>
      <P>(D) The individual conducts activities in close proximity to the election or over a protracted period of time.</P>
      <P>(E) The individual has taken action to qualify for the ballot under State law.</P>

      <P>(2) Any cost incurred in covering or carrying a new story, commentary, or editorial by any broadcasting station (including a cable television operator, programmer or producer), newspaper, magazine, or other periodical publication is not an expenditure unless the facility is owned or controlled by any political party, political committee, or candidate, in which case the costs for a news story (i) which represents a <E T="03">bona fide</E> news account communicated in a publication of general circulation or on a licensed broadcasting facility, and (ii) which is part of a general pattern of campaign-related news account which give reasonably equal coverage to all opposing candidates in the circulation or listening area, is not an expenditure.</P>

      <P>(3) Any cost incurred for activity designed to encourage individuals to register to vote or to vote is not an expenditure if no effort is or has been made to determine the party or candidate preference of individuals before encouraging them to register to vote or to vote, except that corporations and labor organizations shall engage in such activity in accordance with 11 CFR 114.4 (c) and (d). <E T="03">See also</E> 11 CFR 114.3(c)(4)</P>
      <P>(4) Any cost incurred for any communication by a membership organization to its members, or by a corporation to its stockholders or executive or administrative personnel, is not an expenditure, so long as the membership organization or corporation is not organized primarily for the purpose of influencing the nomination for election, or election, of any individual to Federal office, except that the costs incurred by a membership organization, including a labor organization, or by a corporation, directly attributable to a communication expressly advocating the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate (other than a communication primarily devoted to subjects other than the express advocacy of the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate) shall, if those costs exceed $2,000 per election, be reported to the Commission on FEC Form 7 in accordance with 11 CFR 104.6</P>
      <P>(i) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4), <E T="03">labor organization</E> means an organization of any kind (any local, national, or international union, or any local or State central body of a federation of unions is each considered a separate labor organization for purposes of this section) or any agency or employee representative committee or plan, in which employees participate and which exists for the purpose, in whole or in part, of dealing with employers concerning grievances, labor disputes, wages, rates of pay, hours of employment, or conditions of work.</P>
      <P>(ii) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4), <E T="03">stockholder</E> means a person who has a vested beneficial interest in stock, has the power to direct how that stock shall be voted, if it is voting stock, and has the right to receive dividends.</P>
      <P>(iii) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4), <E T="03">executive or administrative personnel</E> means individuals employed by a corporation who are paid on a salary rather than hourly basis and who have policymaking, managerial, professional, or supervisory responsibilities.</P>
      <P>(A) This definition includes—</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) Individuals who run the corporation's business, such as officers, other executives, and plant, division, and section managers; and</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Individuals following the recognized professions, such as lawyers and engineers.</P>
      <P>(B) This definition does not include—</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) Professionals who are represented by a labor organization;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Salaried foremen and other salaried lower level supervisors having direct supervision over hourly employees;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">3</E>) Former or retired personnel who are not stockholders; or</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">4</E>) Individuals who may be paid by the corporation, such as consultants, but who are not employees, within the meaning of 26 CFR 31.3401(c)-(1), of the corporation for the purpose of the collection of, and liability for, employee tax under 26 CFR 31.3402(a)-(1).</P>

      <P>(C) Individuals on commission may be considered executive or administrative personnel if they have policymaking, managerial, professional, or <PRTPAGE P="59"/>supervisory responsibility and if the individuals are employees, within the meaning of 26 CFR 31.3401(c)-(1), of the corporation for the purpose of the collection of, and liability for, employee tax under 26 CFR 31.3402(a)-(1).</P>
      <P>(D) The Fair Labor Standards Act, 29 USC 201, <E T="03">et seq.</E> and the regulations issued pursuant to such Act, 29 CFR part 541, <E T="03">et seq.,</E> may serve as a guideline in determining whether individuals have policymaking, managerial, professional, or supervisory responsibilities.</P>

      <P>(iv) (A) For purposes of paragraph (b)(4)(iv) of this section, <E T="03">membership association</E> means a membership organization, trade association, cooperative, corporation without capital stock, or a local, national, or international labor organization that</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) Expressly provides for “members” in its articles and by-laws;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Expressly solicits members; and</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">3</E>) Expressly acknowledges the acceptance of membership, such as by sending a membership card or inclusion on a membership newsletter list.</P>
      <P>(B) For purposes of paragraph (b)(4) of this section, <E T="03">members</E> means all persons who are currently satisfying the requirements for membership in a membership association, affirmatively accept the membership association's invitation to become a member, and either:</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) Have some significant financial attachment to the membership association, such as a significant investment or ownership stake (but <E T="03">not</E> merely the payment of dues);</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Are required to pay on a regular basis a specific amount of dues that is predetermined by the association and are entitled to vote directly either for at least one member who has full participatory and voting rights on the highest governing body of the membership association, or for those who select at least one member of those on the highest governing body of the membership association; or</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">3</E>) Are entitled to vote directly for all of those on the highest governing body of the membership association.</P>

      <P>(C) Notwithstanding the requirements of paragraph (b)(4)(iv)(B)(<E T="03">2</E>) of this section, the Commission may determine, on a case by case basis, that persons seeking to be considered members of a membership association for purposes of this section have a significant organizational and financial attachment to the association under circumstances that do not precisely meet the requirements of the general rule. For example, student members who pay a lower amount of dues while in school or long term dues paying members who qualify for lifetime membership status with little or no dues obligation may be considered members if they retain voting rights in the association.</P>

      <P>(D) Notwithstanding the requirements of paragraphs (b)(4)(iv)(B)(<E T="03">1</E>) through (<E T="03">3</E>) of this section, members of a local union are considered to be members of any national or international union of which the local union is a part and of any federation with which the local, national, or international union is affiliated.</P>
      <P>(v) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4), <E T="03">election</E> means two separate processes in a calendar year, to each of which the $2,000 threshold described above applies separately. The first process is comprised of all primary elections for Federal office, whenever and wherever held; the second process is comprised of all general elections for Federal office, whenever and wherever held. The term <E T="03">election</E> shall also include each special election held to fill a vacancy in a Federal office (11 CFR 100.2(f)) or each runoff election (11 CFR 100.2(d)).</P>
      <P>(vi) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4), <E T="03">corporation</E> means any separately incorporated entity, whether or not affiliated.</P>
      <P>(vii) When the aggregate costs under 11 CFR 100.8(b)(4) exceed $2,000 per election, all costs of the communication(s) shall be reported on the filing dates specified in 11 CFR 104.6, and shall include the total amount expended for each candidate supported.</P>

      <P>(5) No expenditure results where an individual, in the course of volunteering personal services on his or her residential premises to any candidate or political committee of a political party, provides the use of his or her real or personal property to such candidate for candidate-related activity or to such political committee of a political party for party-related activity. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(5), <PRTPAGE P="60"/>an individual's residential premises shall include a recreation room in a residential complex where the individual volunteering services resides, provided that the room is available for use without regard to political affiliation. A nominal fee paid by such individual for the use of such room is not an expenditure.</P>
      <P>(6) No expenditure results where an individual, in the course of volunteering personal services to any candidate or political committee of a political party, obtains the use of a church or community room and provides such room to any candidate for candidate-related activity or to any political committee of a political party for party-related activity, provided that the room is used on a regular basis by members of the community for noncommercial purposes and the room is available for use by members of the community without regard to political affiliation. A nominal fee paid by such individual for the use of such room is not an expenditure.</P>
      <P>(7) The cost of invitations, food, and beverages is not an expenditure where such items are voluntarily provided by an individual in rendering voluntary personal services on the individual's residential premises or in a church or community room as specified at 11 CFR 100.8(b)(5) and (6) to a candidate for candidate-related activity or to a political committee of a political party for party-related activity, to the extent that: The aggregate value of such invitations, food and beverages provided by the individual on behalf of the candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to any single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in any calendar year.</P>
      <P>(8) The sale of any food or beverage by a vendor (whether incorporated or not) for use in a candidate's campaign, or for use by a political committee of a political party, at a charge less than the normal or comparable commercial charge, is not an expenditure, provided that the charge is at least equal to the cost of such food or beverage to the vendor, to the extent that: The aggregate value of such discount given by the vendor on behalf of any single candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to any single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in a calendar year.</P>
      <P>(9) Any unreimbursed payment for transportation expenses incurred by any individual on behalf of any candidate or political committee of a political party is not an expenditure to the extent that: The aggregate value of the payments made by such individual on behalf of a candidate does not exceed $1,000 with respect to a single election; and on behalf of all political committees of each political party does not exceed $2,000 in a calendar year. Additionally, any unreimbursed payment from a volunteer's personal funds for usual and normal subsistence expenses incident to volunteer activity is not an expenditure.</P>
      <P>(10) The payment by a State or local committee of a political party of the costs of preparation, display, or mailing or other distribution incurred by such committee with respect to a printed slate card, sample ballot, palm card, or other printed listing(s) of three or more candidates for any public office for which an election is held in the State in which the committee is organized is not an expenditure. The payment of the portion of such costs allocable to Federal candidates must be made from funds subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act. If made by a political party committee, such payments shall be reported by that committee as disbursements, but need not be allocated in committee reports to specific candidates. This exemption shall not apply to costs incurred by such a committee with respect to the preparation and display of listings made on broadcasting stations, or in newspapers, magazines, and similar types of general public political advertising such as billboards.</P>
      <P>(11) Any payment made or obligation incurred by a corporation or labor organization is not an expenditure if under the provisions of 11 CFR part 114 such payment or obligation would not constitute an expenditure by the corporation or labor organization.</P>

      <P>(12) A loan of money by a State bank, a federally chartered depository institution (including a national bank) or a depository institution whose deposits <PRTPAGE P="61"/>and accounts are insured by the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration is not an expenditure by the lending institution if such loan is made in accordance with applicable banking laws and regulations and is made in the ordinary course of business. A loan will be deemed to be made in the ordinary course of business if it: Bears the usual and customary interest rate of the lending institution for the category of loan involved; is made on a basis which assures repayment; is evidenced by a written instrument; and is subject to a due date or amortization schedule. Such loans shall be reported by the political committee in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(a). Each endorser or guarantor shall be deemed to have contributed that portion of the total amount of the loan for which he or she agreed to be liable in a written agreement, except that, in the event of a signature by the candidate's spouse, the provisions of 11 CFR 100.7(a)(1)(i)(D) shall apply. Any reduction in the unpaid balance of the loan shall reduce proportionately the amount endorsed or guaranteed by each endorser or guarantor in such written agreement. In the event that the loan agreement does not stipulate the portion of the loan for which each endorser or guarantor is liable, the loan shall be considered an expenditure by each endorser or guarantor in the same proportion to the unpaid balance that each endorser or guarantor bears to the total number of endorsers or guarantors. For the purpose of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(12), an overdraft made on a checking or savings account shall be considered an expenditure unless: The overdraft is made on an account which is subject to automatic overdraft protection; and the overdraft is subject to a definite interest rate and a definite repayment schedule.</P>
      <P>(i) A loan, including a line of credit, shall be considered made on a basis which assures repayment if it is obtained using either of the sources of repayment described in paragraphs (b)(12)(i) (A) or (B) of this section, or a combination of paragraphs (b)(12)(i) (A) and (B) of this section:</P>
      <P>(A)(<E T="03">1</E>) The lending institution making the loan has perfected a security interest in collateral owned by the candidate or political committee receiving the loan; the fair market value of the collateral is equal to or greater than the loan amount and any senior liens as determined on the date of the loan; and the candidate or political committee provides documentation to show that the lending institution has a perfected security interest in the collateral. Sources of collateral include, but are not limited to, ownership in real estate, personal property, goods, negotiable instruments, certificates of deposit, chattel papers, stocks, accounts receivable and cash on deposit.</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Amounts guaranteed by secondary sources of repayment, such as guarantors and cosigners, shall not exceed the contribution limits of 11 CFR part 110 or contravene the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4, part 114 and part 115; or</P>

      <P>(B) The lending institution making the loan has obtained a written agreement whereby the candidate or political committee receiving the loan has pledged future receipts, such as public financing payments under 11 CFR part 9001 <E T="03">et seq.</E> or part 9031 <E T="03">et seq.,</E> contributions, or interest income, provided that:</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">1</E>) The amount of the loan(s) obtained the basis of such funds does not exceed the amount of pledged funds;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">2</E>) Loan amounts are based on a reasonable expectation of the receipt of pledged funds. To that end, the candidate or political committee must furnish the lending institution documentation, i.e., cash flow charts or other financial plans, that reasonably establish that such future funds will be available;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">3</E>) A separate depository account is established at the lending institution or the lender obtains an assignment from the candidate or political committee to access funds in a committee account at another depository institution that meets the requirements of 11 CFR 103.2, and the committee has notified the other institution of this assignment;</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">4</E>) The loan agreement requires the deposit of the public financing payments, contributions, interest or other income pledged as collateral into the <PRTPAGE P="62"/>separate depository account for the purpose of retiring the debt according to the repayment requirements of the loan; and</P>
      <P>(<E T="03">5</E>) In the case of public financing payments, the borrower authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to directly deposit the payments into the depository account for the purpose of retiring the debt.</P>
      <P>(ii) If the requirements set forth in paragraph (b)(12)(i) of this section are not met, the Commission will consider the totality of circumstances on a case-by-case basis in determining whether a loan was made on a basis which assures repayment.</P>
      <P>(13) A purchase, payment, distribution, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value made to a national committee or a state committee of a political party is not an expenditure if it is specifically designated to defray any cost incurred for construction or purchase of any office facility which is not acquired for the purpose of influencing the election of any candidate in any particular election for Federal office. If such purchase, payment, distribution, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value is made to a committee which is not a political committee under 11 CFR 100.5, the amount need not be reported. However, if such purchase, payment, distribution, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value is made to a political committee, it shall be reported in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(g).</P>
      <P>(14) Legal or accounting services rendered to or on behalf of any political committee of a political party are not expenditures if the person paying for such services is the regular employer of the individual rendering the services and such services are not attributable to activities which directly further the election of any designated candidate for Federal office. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(14), a partnership shall be deemed to be the regular employer of a partner. Amounts paid by the regular employer for such services shall be reported by the committee receiving such services in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(h).</P>

      <P>(15) Legal or accounting services rendered to or on behalf of an authorized committee of a candidate or any other political committee are not expenditures if the person paying for such services is the regular employer of the individual rendering such services and if the services are solely to ensure compliance with the Act or 26 U.S.C. 9001 <E T="03">et seq.</E> and 9032 <E T="03">et seq.</E> For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(15), a partnership shall be deemed to be the regular employer of a partner. Amounts paid by the regular employer for these services shall be reported by the committee receiving such services in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3(h). Expenditures for these services by a candidate certified to receive Primary Matching Funds under 11 CFR part 9034 do not count against such candidate's expenditure limitations under 11 CFR part 9035 or 11 CFR 110.8. Unless paid for with federal funds received pursuant to 11 CFR part 9005, disbursements for these services by a candidate who is certified to receive payments from the Presidential Election Campaign Fund under 11 CFR part 9005 do not count against that candidate's expenditure limitations under 11 CFR 110.8.</P>
      <P>(16) The payment by a state or local committee of a political party of the costs of campaign materials (such as pins, bumper stickers, handbills, brochures, posters, party tabloids or newsletters, and yard signs) used by such committee in connection with volunteer activities on behalf of any nominee(s) of such party is not an expenditure, provided that the following conditions are met.</P>

      <P>(i) Such payment is not for costs incurred in connection with any broadcasting, newspaper, magazine, billboard, direct mail, or similar type of general public communication or political advertising. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(16)(i), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means any mailing(s) by a commercial vendor or any mailing(s) made from commercial lists.</P>
      <P>(ii) The portion of the cost of such materials allocable to Federal candidates is paid from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act.</P>

      <P>(iii) Such payment is not made from contributions designated by the donor to be spent on behalf of a particular <PRTPAGE P="63"/>candidate or candidates for Federal office. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(16)(iii), a contribution shall not be considered a <E T="03">designated contribution</E> if the party committee disbursing the funds makes the final decision regarding which candidate(s) shall receive the benefit of such disbursement.</P>
      <P>(iv) Such materials are distributed by volunteers and not by commercial or for-profit operations. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(16)(iv), payments by the party organization for travel and subsistence or customary token payments to volunteers do not remove such individuals from the volunteer category.</P>
      <P>(v) If made by a political party committee, such payments shall be reported by that committee as disbursements, in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3, but need not be allocated to specific candidates in committee reports.</P>
      <P>(vi) Payments by a State candidate or his or her campaign committee to a State or local political party committee for the State candidate's share of expenses for such campaign materials are not expenditures, provided the amount paid by the State candidate or his or her committee does not exceed his or her proportionate share of the expenses.</P>
      <P>(vii) Campaign materials purchased by the national committee of a political party and delivered to a State or local party committee, or materials purchased with funds donated by the national committee to such State or local committee for the purchase of such materials, shall not qualify under this exemption. Rather, the cost of such materials shall be subject to the limitations of 2 U.S.C. 441a(d) and 11 CFR 110.7.</P>

      <P>(17) The payment by a candidate for any public office (including State or local office), or by such candidate's authorized committee, of the costs of that candidate's campaign materials which include information on or any reference to a candidate for Federal office and which are used in connection with volunteer activities (such as pins, bumper stickers, handbills, brochures, posters, and yard signs) is not an expenditure on behalf of such candidate for Federal office, provided that the payment is not for the use of broadcasting, newspapers, magazines, billboards, direct mail or similar types of general public communication or political advertising. The payment of the portion of the cost of such materials allocable to Federal candidates shall be made from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(17), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means mailings by commercial vendors or mailings made from lists which were not developed by the candidate.</P>
      <P>(18) The payment by a State or local committee of a political party of the costs of voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities conducted by such committee on behalf of the Presidential and Vice Presidential nominee(s) of that party is not an expenditure for the purpose of influencing the election of such candidates provided that the following conditions are met:</P>

      <P>(i) Such payment is not for the costs incurred in connection with any broadcasting, newspaper, magazine, billboard, direct mail, or similar type of general public communication or political advertising. For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(18)(i), the term <E T="03">direct mail</E> means any mailing(s) by a commercial vendor or any mailing(s) made from commercial lists.</P>
      <P>(ii) The portion of the costs of such activities allocable to Federal candidates is paid from contributions subject to the limitations and prohibitions of the Act.</P>

      <P>(iii) Such payment is not made from contributions designated to be spent on behalf of a particular candidate or candidates for Federal office. For the purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(18)(iii), a contribution shall not be considerd a <E T="03">designated contribution</E> if the party committee disbursing the funds makes the final decision regarding which candidate(s) shall receive the benefit of such disbursement.</P>

      <P>(iv) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(18), if such activities include references to any candidate(s) for the House or Senate, the costs of such activities which are allocable to that candidate(s) shall be an expenditure on behalf of such candidate(s) unless the mention of such candidate(s) is merely incidental to the overall activity.<PRTPAGE P="64"/>
      </P>
      <P>(v) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(b)(18), payment of the costs incurred in the use of phone banks in connection with voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities is not an expenditure when such phone banks are operated by volunteer workers. The use of paid professionals to design the phone bank system, develop calling instructions and train supervisors is permissible. The payment of the costs of such professional services is not an expenditure but shall be reported as a disbursement in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3 if made by a political committee.</P>
      <P>(vi) If made by a political committee, such payments for voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities shall be reported by that committee as disbursements, in accordance with 11 CFR 104.3 but such payments need not be allocated to specific candidates in committee reports except as provided in 11 CFR 100.8(b)(18)(iv).</P>
      <P>(vii) Payments made from funds donated by a national committee of a political party to a State or local party committee for voter registration and get-out-the-vote activities shall not qualify under this exemption. Rather, such funds shall be subject to the limitations of 2 U.S.C. 441a(d) and 11 CFR 110.7.</P>
      <P>(19) Amounts transferred by a party committee to another party committee or payments made to the appropriate State official of fees collected from candidates or their authorized committees as a condition of ballot access are not expenditures.</P>
      <P>(20) A purchase, payment, distribution, loan, advance, or deposit of money or anything of value made with respect to a recount of the results of a Federal election, or an election contest concerning a Federal election, is not an expenditure except that the prohibitions of 11 CFR 110.4(a) and part 114 apply.</P>
      <P>(21)(i) Any costs incurred by a candidate or his or her authorized committee(s) in connection with the solicitation of contributions are not expenditures if incurred by a candidate who has been certified to receive Presidential Primary Matching Fund Payments, or by a candidate who has been certified to receive general election public financing under 26 U.S.C. 9004 and who is soliciting contributions in accordance with 26 U.S.C. 9003(b)(2) or 9003(c)(2) to the extent that the aggregate of such costs does not exceed 20 percent of the expenditure limitation applicable to the candidate. These costs shall, however, be reported as disbursements pursuant to 11 CFR part 104.</P>

      <P>(ii) For a candidate who has been certified to receive general election public financing under 26 U.S.C. 9004 and who is soliciting contributions in accordance with 26 U.S.C. 9003(b)(2) or 9003(c)(2), <E T="03">in connection with the solicitation of contributions</E> means any cost reasonably related to fundraising activity, including the costs of printing and postage, the production of and space or air time for, advertisements used for fundraising, and the costs of meals, beverages, and other costs associated with a fundraising reception or dinner.</P>
      <P>(iii) For a candidate who has been certified to receive Presidential Primary Matching Fund Payments, the costs that may be exempted as fundraising expenses under this section shall not exceed 20% of the overall expenditure limitation under 11 CFR 9035.1, and shall equal the total of:</P>
      <P>(A) All amounts excluded from the state expenditure limitations for exempt fundraising activities under 11 CFR 110.8(c)(2), plus</P>
      <P>(B) An amount of costs that would otherwise be chargeable to the overall expenditure limitation but that are not chargeable to any state expenditure limitation, such as salary and travel expenses. See 11 CFR 106.2.</P>
      <P>(22) Payments by a candidate from his or her personal funds, as defined at 11 CFR 110.10(b), for the candidate's routine living expenses which would have been incurred without candidacy, including the cost of food and residence, are not expenditures. Payments for such expenses by a member of the candidate's family as defined in 11 CFR 113.1(g)(7), are not expenditures if the payments are made from an account jointly held with the candidate, or if the expenses were paid by the family member before the candidate became a candidate.</P>

      <P>(23) Funds used to defray costs incurred in staging candidate debates in <PRTPAGE P="65"/>accordance with the provisions of 11 CFR 110.13 and 114.4(f).</P>
      <P>(c) For purposes of 11 CFR 100.8(a) and (b), a payment made by an individual shall not be attributed to any other individual, unless otherwise specified by that other individual. To the extent that a payment made by an individual qualifies as a contribution, the provisions of 11 CFR 110.1(k) shall apply.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980; 45 FR 23642, Apr. 8, 1980, as amended at 45 FR 43387, June 27, 1980; 48 FR 19020, Apr. 27, 1983; 50 FR 9994, Mar. 13, 1985; 52 FR 773, Jan. 9, 1987; 56 FR 35908, July 29, 1991; 56 FR 67123, Dec. 27, 1991; 58 FR 45774, Aug. 30, 1993; 60 FR 7874, Feb. 9, 1995; 60 FR 64272, Dec. 14, 1995; 61 FR 18051, Apr. 24, 1996]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.9</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Commission (2 U.S.C. 431(10)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Commission</E> means the Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.10</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Person (2 U.S.C. 431(11)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Person</E> means an individual, partnership, committee, association, corporation, labor organization, and any other organization, or group of persons, but does not include the Federal government or any authority of the Federal government.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.11</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>State (2 U.S.C. 431(12)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">State</E> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and any territory or possession of the United States.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.12</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Identification (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Identification</E> means, in the case of an individual, his or her full name, including: First name, middle name or initial, if available, and last name; mailing address; occupation; and the name of his or her employer; and, in the case of any other person, the person's full name and address.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.13</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>National committee (2 U.S.C. 431(14)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">National committee</E> means the organization which, by virtue of the bylaws of a political party, is responsible for the day-to-day operation of the political party at the national level, as determined by the Commission.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.14</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>State committee, subordinate committee (2 U.S.C. 431(15)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>(a) <E T="03">State committee</E> means the organization which by virtue of the bylaws of a political party, is responsible for the day-to-day operation of the political party at the State level, as determined by the Commission.</P>
      <P>(b) <E T="03">Subordinate committee of a State committee</E> means any organization which is responsible for the day-to-day operation of the political party at the level of city, county, neighborhood, ward, district, precinct, or any other subdivision of a State or any organization under the control or direction of the State committee.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.15</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Political party (2 U.S.C. 431(16)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Political party</E> means an association, committee, or organization which nominates or selects a candidate for election to any Federal office, whose name appears on an election ballot as the candidate of the association, committee, or organization.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.16</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Independent expenditure (2 U.S.C. 431(17)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>The term <E T="03">independent expenditure</E> means an expenditure for a communication by a person expressly advocating the election or defeat of a clearly identified candidate which is made without cooperation or consultation with any candidate, or any authorized committee or agent of such candidate, and which is not made in concert with, or at the request or suggestion of, any candidate, or any authorized committee or agent of such candidate.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.17</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Clearly identified (2 U.S.C. 431(18)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>The term <E T="03">clearly identified</E> means the candidate's name, nickname, photograph, or drawing appears, or the identity of the candidate is otherwise apparent through an unambiguous reference such as “the President,” “your Congressman,” or “the incumbent,” or through an unambiguous reference to his or her status as a candidate such as <PRTPAGE P="66"/>“the Democratic presidential nominee” or “the Republican candidate for Senate in the State of Georgia.”</P>
      <CITA>[60 FR 35304, July 6, 1995]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.18</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Act (2 U.S.C. 431(19)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Act</E> means the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (Pub. L. 92-225), as amended in 1974 (Pub. L. 93-443), 1976 (Pub. L. 94-283), 1977 (Pub. L. 95-216) and 1980 (Pub. L. 96-187).</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.19</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>File, filed or filing (2 U.S.C. 434(a)).</SUBJECT>

      <P>With respect to reports, statements, notices, and designations required to be filed under 11 CFR parts 101, 102, 104, 105, 107, 108 and 109, and any modifications or amendments thereto, the terms <E T="03">file, filed</E> and <E T="03">filing</E> mean either of the following actions:</P>
      <P>(a) A document is timely filed upon delivery to the Federal Election Commission, 999 E Street, NW., Washington, DC 20463; or the Secretary of the United States Senate, Office of Public Records, 119 D Street NE., Washington, DC 20510 as required by 11 CFR part 105, by the close of the prescribed filing date.</P>
      <P>(b) A document is timely filed upon deposit as registered or certified mail in an established U.S. Post Office and postmarked no later than midnight of the day of the filing date, except that pre-election reports so mailed must be postmarked no later than midnight of the fifteenth day before the date of the election. Reports and statements sent by first class mail must be received by the close of business of the prescribed filing date to be timely filed.</P>
      <CITA>[45 FR 15094, Mar. 7, 1980, as amended at 50 FR 50778, Dec. 12, 1985; 61 FR 6095, Feb. 16, 1996]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.20</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Occupation (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Occupation</E> means the principal job title or position of an individual and whether or not self-employed.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.21</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Employer (2 U.S.C. 431(13)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Employer</E> means the organization or person by whom an individual is employed, and not the name of his or her supervisor.</P>
    </SECTION>
    <SECTION>
      <SECTNO>§ 100.22</SECTNO>
      <SUBJECT>Expressly advocating (2 U.S.C. 431(17)).</SUBJECT>
      <P>
        <E T="03">Expressly advocating</E> means any communication that—(a) Uses phrases such as “vote for the President,” “re-elect your Congressman,” “support the Democratic nominee,” “cast your ballot for the Republican challenger for U.S. Senate in Georgia,” “Smith for Congress,” “Bill McKay in ‘94,” “vote Pro-Life” or “vote Pro-Choice” accompanied by a listing of clearly identified candidates described as Pro-Life or Pro-Choice, “vote against Old Hickory,” “defeat” accompanied by a picture of one or more candidate(s), “reject the incumbent,” or communications of campaign slogan(s) or individual word(s), which in context can have no other reasonable meaning than to urge the election or defeat of one or more clearly identified candidate(s), such as posters, bumper stickers, advertisements, etc. which say “Nixon's the One,” “Carter ’76,” “Reagan/Bush” or “Mondale!”; or</P>
      <P>(b) When taken as a whole and with limited reference to external events, such as the proximity to the election, could only be interpreted by a reasonable person as containing advocacy of the election or defeat of one or more clearly identified candidate(s) because—</P>
      <P>(1) The electoral portion of the communication is unmistakable, unambiguous, and suggestive of only one meaning; and</P>
      <P>(2) Reasonable minds could not differ as to whether it encourages actions to elect or defeat one or more clearly identified candidate(s) or encourages some other kind of action.</P>
      <CITA>[60 FR 35304, July 6, 1995]</CITA>
    </SECTION>
  </PART>
</CFRGRANULE>
